# Saravanakumar Kathiravan

+91 9047396553 ● iamsarank@gmail.com ● linkedin.com/in/saravanakumar-kathiravan/

#### SUMMARY

Creative UI Developer with 3 years facilitating and supporting human interactions with complex systems and software. Maintains user-centric designs while adhering to prescribed interface principals and related development goals. Dedicated to creating inviting and unintimidating interfaces for everything from simple open-source applications to complex proprietary systems.

## **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE**

# LOOKMAN ELECTROPLAST IN LTD. UI Developer

Sept 2021 - Dec 2024

- Collaborate with designers and back-end developers to implement user-friendly and visually appealing interfaces
- Develop reusable UI components using React, RESTful APIs ensuring consistency across the application
- · Optimize front-end performance to ensure fast load times and smooth user experiences
- Implement and maintain front-end features using React and Redux, dynamic charts and graphs with realtime data updates
- Implement responsive design principles to ensure applications work seamlessly across devices
- Conduct user testing and gather feedback to improve the usability of web applications
- Communicated with product managers and UX designers to translate project requirements and business objectives into polished user interfaces.
- Developed application UIs via emerging front-end technologies.
- Used wireframes, mock-ups and prototypes to establish user interface design and architecture.
- Enhanced user experience by implementing innovative and responsive UI designs.

# • EVENTJINI - INTERN

Dec 2020 - Sept 2021

# **UI Developer**

- Translated design mockups into functional front-end code using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams, including back-end developers and project managers, to deliver high-quality web applications
- Collaborated with designers to translate wireframes and mockups into high-quality code
- Worked with design teams, project managers and business analysts to create intuitive and easy-to-use
- software.
- Enhanced user experience by implementing innovative and responsive UI designs.
- Used wireframes, mock-ups and prototypes to establish user interface design and architecture.

## **EDUCATION**

**PSG College of Technology, Coimbatore** 

Ayya Nadar Janaki Ammal College, Sivakasi

Master of Computer Applications | 2017 - 2020

B.Sc Computer Science | 2014 - 2017

### **SKILLS**

**Front-End Development:** HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript (ES6+), ReactJS, Bootstrap, Tailwind CSS, Material UI **Tools & Technologies**: Git, npm, Webpack, RESTful APIs, Responsive Web Design, Cross-Browser Compatibility

Other: UX/UI Design, Wireframing, Prototyping, Agile Methodologies